<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-12T12:41:11-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Money2Wealth</title><subtitle>One place to learn how to grow your money and become wealthy.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Many ways to make Income!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/types-of-income/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Many ways to make Income!" /><published>2022-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-21T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/types-of-income</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/types-of-income/">&lt;p&gt;Many ways to make Income&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income is often associated with salary or a job where you receive a regular paycheck in exchange for your time and work to the organization you work for. It is natural for us all to think so as we so a large proportion of people in close family and friends who work in a job and get an income. But, there is more to an income and lets understand it more below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Income can be deconstructed as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;IN&lt;/code&gt; plus &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;COMING&lt;/code&gt;  and has a literal dictionary meaning as &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;the money an individual or business entity earns in exchange of time, services, goods or value&lt;/code&gt;. In this article we will look at some of the common types of money inflow that people create for themselves. These are high level categories &amp;amp; multiple activities that one carries out to make money would most certainly fall under one of these categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;renting-your-time&quot;&gt;Renting Your Time&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, we as humans trade our time for money (aka job). When you consider time as an asset, it’s easy to see that the asset you have is being rented by someone in exchange of a fee they are willing to pay. How much they pay depends on how they can utilize your time e.g. if you work as labourer, you are trading your physical efforts; if you are a mechanic, you are still trading your physical efforts however along with some specialized skills; if you are a dietitian, you are trading your knowledge etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hence the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;money&lt;/code&gt; paid per unit of time depends on “what you do”, “what you know”, “where you work” or a combination of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This category of income has lower upfront capital needs to get started &lt;!-- TODO: Link to article on Capex vs Opex --&gt; with an exception of specialized domains with specific needs taking years of time investment to learn those skills (e.g. doctors, pilots etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- selling services also comes in this category --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;selling-your-skills&quot;&gt;selling your skills&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are skilled, period. You have your own set of experiences that accumulated over the years. You may like to write books or blogs, you may be a music instrument enthusiast playing piano or guitar, you may be a barista or a chef or a baker. Bottom like, you are unique, and your skill has value as some one else is there to learn from you. This is the current internet economy of content creators,  influencers and teachers online. The income you generate by teaching and communicating your skills is an income stream that generate continues money flow 24*7 as internet never sleeps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cost-arbitrage&quot;&gt;Cost Arbitrage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are selling a product, most likely you are either building something &amp;amp; selling, or,  you are buying something at a lower price &amp;amp; selling at a higher price. 
The later one, is when you make money by cost arbitrage. Example: buying stuff from point of creation &amp;amp; selling it at point of consumption (aka trading merchant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of activity usually has a very low entry barrier (unless you are sourcing items or people that are difficult to find), that’s why you see a lot of kiraana shops all around you in India. Low entry barriers also means that multiple people will start the same business &amp;amp; the outcome is reduced profit margins for everybody as the supply is now higher for the same amount of demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;money-making-money&quot;&gt;Money making Money&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- fixed income assets, gold etc  --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have your spending habits in a way that you save some money each month, you can put it to work for you by investing in various instruments (aka means of investment). Some of these give you back a regular payment (in the form of interest or dividend), some of them just grow in value (e.g. gold, real estate) depending on market conditions. In both the cases, you have created a secondary source of income, a small yet significant first step to gain wealth over the years !! The ways, means, nuances, methods and techniques of investing into assets to build streams of income is a very vast never ending topic that will be discussed in details on our platform. so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;selling-goods--services&quot;&gt;Selling Goods &amp;amp; Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider this the most satisfying way of making money. Essentially, you create a business where you either manufacture products or sell services, build a team and create employment opportunities, thus making lives better.
Selling services here is different from the point above about trading time. If you are working alone, yes you are trading your time by providing services, however if you are a business that employs people to sell services, you have scaled that effort multiple times.
Selling good and services as a business is a common method to leverage your current experiences and expertise to scale them to serve a larger number of customers. The income generated in such enterprises is often categorized as small business income or corporate income in some more mature businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inheritance-gifts-allowance--lottery&quot;&gt;Inheritance, Gifts, Allowance &amp;amp; Lottery&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are lucky, you don’t need to do anything for this one. Either your elders, employer, government or someone else is giving you a stream of money. This stream however may not be lifelong. It’ll either by one-time or time-bound money flow coming your way. If you use this opportunity wisely, you can create more income streams for yourself. Read the KBC example in the article &lt;Rich vs=&quot;&quot; Wealthy=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/Rich&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gist&quot;&gt;gist&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now you may have realized Income is not just from job, income can be in many forms and functions. What is often missing is our ability to realize how to create these income streams. It is said that most successful people have at least 7 sources of income. In some of the future blog posts, we’ll talk about what these are &amp;amp; how to create them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, just remember one point: It takes time to become wealthy. No shortcuts.  If you understand the power compounding, you’ll understand the point above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be curious to know if your income source falls in one of these categories, please write back in the comments section &amp;amp; let us know !!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>himanshu</name></author><category term="concepts" /><category term="basics" /><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">Many ways to make Income</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/money_001.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/money_001.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sadly rich or Happily wealthy ?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/rich-vs-wealth/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sadly rich or Happily wealthy ?" /><published>2022-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-14T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/rich-vs-wealth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/rich-vs-wealth/">&lt;p&gt;Sadly rich or Happily wealthy ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know why many rich people end up poor and wealthy stay wealthy for generations ? Have you always wanted to be rich? or Do you want to be wealthy? This is a confusion that is present in almost everyone’s mind and we all get it mixed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we go too far, a small exercise to see how you think ?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Answer the questions below as best you can, 
&lt;em&gt;write your answer on a small sheet of paper.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;of these 3 people, Who is rich?
a) Vijay Malya
b) Anil Ambani
c) Nirav Modi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Of these 3 people, Who is wealthy?
a) Mukesh Ambani
b) Ratan Tata
c) Mahendar Singh Dhoni&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is your answer? For the first, if you said Vijay Malya or Anil Ambani or Nirav Modi you are correct. All three were rich, they are not rich anymore, they are in deep debt as they misused their richness. They all had large amounts of money with them Vijay Malya (~11000 Crore INR), Anil Ambani (~5500 Crore INR), Nirav Modi (~8000 Crore INR) were the reported numbers. Now, they are either absconding from the country and owe huge amounts of debt to different banks and financial institutions or are struggling to return the money to their lenders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the second, if you said a) Mukesh Ambani or b) Ratan Tata or c) Mahendra Singh Dhoni, you are correct, all 3 are wealthy. They were always disciplined in their spending, worked hard in their life and were fortunate to have the opportunity come their way.  Mukesh Ambani (~90B USD), Ratan Tata (~1B USD), MS Dhoni (~120M USD). They live inspiring and happy lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why is that 1 set of 3 were rich and lost it all, and the other 3 are wealthy and happy and flourishing and growing. It’s because one focussed on being rich and enjoying the richness, while the other set focussed on building and growing wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;richness-can-be-temporary-wealth-stays-for-generations-and-lifetimes&quot;&gt;Richness can be temporary, wealth stays for generations and lifetimes.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richness alone brings immediate short term relief and happiness, being wealthy brings cumulative and compounding growth over a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, we need both richness and wealth. Being rich and using money with discipline helps us to obtain comforts of life, a good house, a good car, healthy and good quality food etc. Being wealthy helps us to generate more ways to earn money, build a safety net for ourselves and our children and families, and gives us comfort of mind that we have stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does being rich look like? A wise and knowledgeable person will use their money to become mentally and physically healthy and be happy by doing good things and learning new skills.  A person misusing money will buy expensive car, buy gold jewelry, buy expensive alcohol, eat in expensive restaurants, go on luxury travels and as a result waste or squander the money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Wealthy person focuses his/her efforts on building assets (income generating real estate), invest in public company stocks, start and grow businesses, own lots of profit generating businesses while living a comfortable and happy life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sadly-rich-and-happily-wealthy&quot;&gt;Sadly rich and happily wealthy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take another situation, we have 2 people, 1 is richness minded and the other is wealth minded. They both win 1 Crore INR in Kaun Banega Crorepati. What does their financial health look like in 3 years after winning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner of Kaun Banega Crorepati becomes rich only to become poor again in 3 years due to poor choices.  You know why ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;input INR 100,00,000
40% tax cut -&amp;gt; 60,00,000
20% lavish vacation and lifestyle -&amp;gt; 40,00,000
20% expensive car -&amp;gt; 20,00,000
15% maintain expensive lifestyle ( petrol, shopping etc.) -&amp;gt; 5,00,000 ( aka back to square one)
At the end of 3 years -&amp;gt; 5,00,000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wealth minded person invests and grows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;input INR 100,00,000
40% tax cut -&amp;gt; 60,00,000
10% improve quality of life -&amp;gt; 50,00,000
10% support parents and family -&amp;gt; 40,00,000
Rest is invested with 15% annual compounding growth rat.
at the end of 3 years -&amp;gt; 60,83,500&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The richness minded person changed his/her lifestyle and spent all the money. The wealth minded person grew his wealth to 60 Lakhs while also using money to bring happiness in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It is upon us to choose a life of discipline and become wealthy or be rich and spend our money to gain a short term rich feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gist&quot;&gt;gist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staying disciplined is the goal to save and invest wisely and become wealthy. Richness and ability to spend money on good things in life comes automatically &lt;del&gt;as&lt;/del&gt; a by product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;3 principles of growing wealth 
1) Spend with discipline
2) Save and invest wisely
3) Stay committed for long term growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is our only purpose here at Money2Wealth to help you understand and apply principles which show you how to become wealthy while staying rich. sign up to our updates to get the latest knowledge and principles to help yourself become wealthy.
~~~~
Wishing you loads of richness and wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Team Money2Wealth.in&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>aman</name></author><category term="concepts" /><category term="basics" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">Sadly rich or Happily wealthy ?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/money_002.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/money_002.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>